# **Dayan Madushanka Dias**

New York, NY 11109 | 929-288-6725 | dayandias20@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/dayan-dias | Portfolio

#### **PROFILE**

Master's student at Pace University specializing in software development with over 7 years of experience as a professional high caliber Naval Officer and over 2 years of experience in Java, DBMS, Multithreaded application and web technologies.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Pace University, Seidenberg School of Computer Science and Information Systems

New York, NY

Master of Science (MS) in Computer Science

May 2021

**GPA:** 3.90

## University of Kelaniya, Faculty of Science

Colombo, Sri Lanka

Bachelor of Naval Studies in Maritime Warfare

August 2015

**GPA:** 3.33 | **Honors:** Second Class (Upper Division) Honors

### **RELEVANT COURSEWORK**

Mobile Web Development (Responsive Web Development) | Parallel and Distributed Computing (Multithreaded and client-server applications) | Concepts and Structures in Internet Computing | Database Management Systems | Data Mining | Algorithms and Computer Theory | Fundamental Computer Science | and | | Computer Systems and Concepts

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: JAVA, C++, Python, JavaScript, React.js, Ionic Angular Web Applications: HTML5, CSS, XML, JSON, AJAX, Node.js, Express.js

Operating Systems: Windows OS, IOS, Android

Database: MySQL

Software: Adobe Creative Cloud (Adobe XD, Acrobat), Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel,

Access), WEKA, GIMP

### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

## **Predicting Liver Infection in Blood Test Dataset**

April 2020 - June 2020

 Analyze a dataset of 'blood tests' in WEKA data mining tool using different data models to develop a prediction regarding liver infection diagnosis based on various sanguineous factors.

# **Responsive Web Development**

 Developed a responsive website using HTML, CSS and JS to display various projects I have completed individually and collaboratively.

## **Development of Web based application**

• In the process of designing and developing a web-based application using React web framework to bring job seekers, employers and freelancers into a single platform, which will assist them in finding potential employers or employees (git-repo).

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Sri Lanka Navy Sri Lanka

Lieutenant, Staff Officer (Foreign Cooperation)

July 2015 - September 2017

- Established MySQL databases for 'Bilateral and multilateral engagements with foreign navies' and 'Galle Dialogue Maritime Symposium', both which had various data of over 72 navies, which minimized 30% of time and effort, while maintaining data security and accuracy.
- Provided strategic consulting and political analysis for the Commander of the Navy in bilateral/multilateral engagements with other navies, which lead to acquire 4 ships and initiate bilateral engagements with 2 foreign navies.

Sub Lieutenant July 2010 – July 2015

- Maintained highest naval professionalism while serving onboard various ships and craft in different capacities.
- Initiated and conducted more than 100 trainings for officers and sailors on emergency procedures and seamanship, which increased individual performance of personal by 23%.

# **AWARDS**

**Sri Lanka Navy** 'Sword of Honor' for the best Midshipman and 'Highest Aggregator' of the intake of Naval Officers November 2012 **ACTIVITIES** 

Club Name: Pace Computing Society, Member April 2020 – Present

#### SKILLS

Persuasion, Collaboration, Adaptability, Emotional Intelligence, Analytical Reasoning.